{
  "para_original_question": [
    {
      "original_question": "how long does eq bank hold my funds for",
      "question": "How long does the bank eq keep my funds for",
      "answer": "generally we hold funds deposited by cheque or electronic funds transfer eft for five business days beginning after the date of deposit. this means that funds held will actually become available by the sixth business day when you include the date of deposit. for example if you make a deposit on a monday you can access the funds on the following tuesday. although the deposit is reflected immediately in your account balance you won t be able to withdraw or transfer your funds until the hold period has passed. however during the hold period you still earn interest on the deposit amount. for more details check out our hold funds policy."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "who is eq bank",
      "question": "which is eq bank",
      "answer": "eq bank offers canadians a digital banking experience. we launched officially in january 2016 with a commitment to help canadians get the most out of their money. based in toronto eq bank is a trademark of equitable bank. equitable bank is a federally regulated schedule i bank with over 900 employees across canada. dollars"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "who is equitable bank",
      "question": "which is a fair bank",
      "answer": "equitable bank canada s challenger banktm is the country s ninth largest independent schedule i bank. eq bank is the digital arm of equitable bank. you can learn more by visiting www.equitablebank.ca. dollars"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "how does eq bank make money",
      "question": "How does the bank eq make money",
      "answer": "good question banks typically make money by accepting deposits from customers and then providing loans to other customers and earning interest from those loans. we use the deposits from eq bank to furnish equitable bank s residential and commercial loans and earn interest. as a branchless bank we re able to reduce our operating costs and pass on those savings to you in the form of a great everyday interest rate on the savings plus account."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "is eq bank hiring i want to come work for you",
      "question": "I want to come work for you.",
      "answer": "we re always looking for good people check out our latest job postings."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "how do i open an eq bank account",
      "question": "How to open a bank account eq",
      "answer": "it s really easy you can open an account by visiting www.eqbank.ca and applying online."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "who can open an eq bank account",
      "question": "which can open a bank account eq",
      "answer": "all eq bank customers must be a canadian resident meet their province s age of majority 18 or 19 years old depending on where you live have a social insurance number please note eq bank is not available in quebec."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank pull my credit report when i open an account",
      "question": "Bank eq pulls my credit report when I open an account",
      "answer": "as part of our online identity verification process we do a soft credit check meaning your credit score won t be affected and won t be visible to other third parties who view your credit report."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "why do i need to provide my social insurance number sin when opening an account",
      "question": "Why do I have to provide my sin social insurance number when opening an account",
      "answer": "the income tax act requires all banks to obtain your social insurance number when you open an account that earns interest this includes the savings plus account and gics . banks are required to report the interest you earn each year to the canada revenue agency."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank support mint",
      "question": "done eq bank support menth",
      "answer": "we don t officially support access to your savings plus account through mint."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank offer business accounts",
      "question": "eq bank offers business accounts",
      "answer": "unfortunately we do not currently offer business accounts. the savings plus account is for personal use only. dollars"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "why is eq bank asking me to verify my identity through canada post",
      "question": "why eq bank asks me to verify my identity through post canada",
      "answer": "if we re unable to verify your identity through transunion a credit reporting agency you can do so by visiting canada post. similar to showing your government issued photo id at a bank branch we ve partnered with canada post to make verifying your identity as quick and convenient as possible. find the participating canada post outlet that s closest to you."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what do i need to bring with me to canada post",
      "question": "what should I bring with me to Canada post",
      "answer": "you ll need to bring 1 piece of government issued photo id 1 proof of address document if your photo id doesn t have your current address your canada post dss number see what is my canada post dss number and why is it important? dollars"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what types of photo id are accepted by canada post",
      "question": "what types of id photos are accepted by canada post",
      "answer": "canada post will validate your identity based on the information you provided for your eq bank account application. your government issued photo id cannot be expired and the first and last name address and birthdate must be an exact match to the information you provided to us. you ll need to show one of the following pieces of government issued photo id canadian driver s license provincial or territorial photo id card canadian secure certificate of indian status canadian passport canadian permanent resident card"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what proof of address documents do i need to bring to canada post",
      "question": "what proof of address the documents I need to bring to Canada post",
      "answer": "if your government issued photo id doesn t list your current address you ll also need to show a proof of address document such as recent utility bill residential telephone cable tv public utilities commission hydro gas or water residential lease residential mortgage statement or agreement rental agreement lease agreement of purchase and sale school college or university report card or transcript municipal tax notice canada child tax benefit statement most recent income tax assessment government cheque or government cheque stub with individual s name and address statement of employment insurance benefits paid t4e canada pension plan statement of contributions quebec pension plan statement of participation statement of benefits from provincial workplace safety or insurance board statement of direct deposit for provincial works or provincial disability support program attestation of residence issued by the responsible authorities shelters soup kitchens student senior residence long term care facilities aboriginal reserves work camps statement of old age security t4a or statement of canada pension plan benefits t4ap"
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what is my canada post dss number and why is it important",
      "question": "what is my post canada dss number and why is it important",
      "answer": "if we re unable to verify your identity through transunion a credit reporting agency you can do so by visiting canada post and providing your dss number. a dss number or barcode is given to canada post so they can validate your identity based on the information in your application on our behalf. your canada post dss number will be emailed to you but if you can t find it feel free to call our customer care team."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "im trying to open an eq bank account but i dont bank with one of the listed banks what do i do",
      "question": "Im trying to open a bank account eq but I don't know bank with one of the listed banks what I do",
      "answer": "as part of our online identity verification process we may ask you to sign in to one of the banks below to validate your identity atb financial bmo cibc coast capital savings desjardins hsbc laurentian bank meridian national bank rbc scotiabank simplii tangerine td bank vancity if you do not bank with any of the companies listed above you can simply skip this step."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "why am i being directed to contact transunion to request an online consumer disclosure",
      "question": "Why have I been ordered to contact the union to request an online disclosure of consumers?",
      "answer": "an online consumer disclosure is a detailed report of all the information on your credit file and serves as a way for you to check the data as reported to transunion. the information you provide in your eq bank application must be an exact match to what is on your transunion credit file."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank offer foreign exchange or usd accounts",
      "question": "eq bank offers foreign exchange accounts or usd",
      "answer": "eq bank deals with canadian currency only. we don t offer foreign exchange or usd accounts at the moment. we do however offer cheap fast and easy to use international money transfers. you can learn more about them here."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what type of products does eq bank offer",
      "question": "What type of products offers eq bank",
      "answer": "we offer a high interest savings account savings plus account tfsa savings account rsp savings account and gics guaranteed investment certificates ."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "can a non resident open a bank account in canada",
      "question": "may a non-resident open a bank account in Canada",
      "answer": "unfortunately not at the moment. all eq bank customers must be canadian residents in order to open and maintain an account."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank look at my credit score when i sign up",
      "question": "eq bank looks at my credit score when I register",
      "answer": "as part of our online identity verification process we conduct a soft credit check which doesn t affect your personal credit score. your credit score is not considered when opening an eq bank account."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "does eq bank have a referral program",
      "question": "eq bank has a referral program",
      "answer": "we do and thanks for wanting to tell others about us to share your referral link sign in and click on refer a friend."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "how do i find my account number",
      "question": "how to find my account number",
      "answer": "sign in to eq bank and from the dashboard click on your savings accounts. each account has a unique nine digit number associated with it."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "how do i deposit a cheque using the eq bank mobile app",
      "question": "How do I deposit a cheque using the eqbank mobile app",
      "answer": "it s easy simply sign in to your account using the eq bank mobile app. in the bottom right corner click on deposit. enter the dollar value of the cheque in the amount field then select the account you wish to deposit the funds into. take a photo of both the front and back of the cheque then click deposit."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "what kind of fees are associated with my savings plus account",
      "question": "what kind of fees are associated with my savings account plus",
      "answer": "we re all about zero monthly banking fees we don t charge account fees fees for sending or receiving interac e transfers\u00ae fees for bill payments overdraft fees or dormant account fees. after all your money is your money. check out the full list of fees we don t charge."
    },
    {
      "original_question": "how do i set up a direct deposit to my savings plus account",
      "question": "how to configure a direct deposit to my savings account plus",
      "answer": "using the eq bank mobile app sign in to your account then click on the navigation menu in the top right corner. click on set up direct deposit then download void cheque."
    }
  ]
}